Guide to the Hammond family business papers,1835-1916.
Hammond family business papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Hammond family business papers, 1835-1916.
2139
6.5 cubic ft., 126 v.
Correspondence, Financial Records, Legal Documents, Research Materials
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, grocery and general merchandise daybooks, cashbooks, customers' ledgers, inventories, order books, checkbooks and other accounts mainly of Hammond Brothers, the Hammond Store, and [E.J.] Barker and [Wallace] Wyman, successors to the Hammonds; also records relating to company railroad employees, canal and lake steamer shipping accounts, and journals of the Crown Point Iron Company and the Sugar Hill Company.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Members of the Hammond family owned and operated the Crown Point Iron Company, the Sugar Hill Company, and the Hammond Store in various configurations. The Crown Point Iron Company operated under various names, including Penfield and [Timothy] Taft, Penfield and [Eleazor] Harwood, Penfield & Hammond, and John and Thomas Hammond. Allen Penfield and Charles Franklin Hammond were brothers-in-law.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
The bulk of these papers consist of grocery and general merchandise daybooks, cashbooks, customers' ledgers, inventories, order books, checkbooks and other accounts (80 v., 1851-1854, 1872-1916) mainly of Hammond Brothers (John and Thomas), the Hammond Store, and [E.J.] Barker and [Wallace] Wyman, successors (1871) to the Hammonds; also cashbooks, payroll records and board bills for furnace, furnace store, and company railroad employees, canal and lake steamer shipping accounts, and journals (7 v., 1858-1880) of the Crown Point Iron Company; accounts for the furnace company store, which include daybooks, customers' ledgers, and a cashbook (11 v., 1874-1886); miscellaneous accounts (11 v., 1847-1889) of Hammond & Company, Charles Franklin Hammond, the Sugar Hill Company, and others; bankbooks (10 v., 1835-1866) and checkbook stubs (13 v., 1855-1883), covering accounts which C. F. Hammond and Hammond & Company had with banks in Whitehall and Troy; and one daybook of Allen Penfield (1845-1861). In addition to bound account books, the papers also include correspondence, financial statements, orders, invoices, vouchers, board and freight bills, boat operation receipts, general store bills and receipts, and memoranda notebooks. Essex County.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Hammond family.; Barker, E. J.; Hammond, Charles Franklin.; Hammond, John Cross.; Hammond, Thomas.; Harwood, Eleazor.; Penfield, Allen.; Taft, Timothy.; Wyman, Wallace.; Crown Point Iron Company (Crown Point, N.Y.); Hammond Store (Crown Point, N.Y.); Penfield & Hammond (Crown Point, N.Y.); Penfield & Harwood (Crown Point, N.Y.); Penfield & Taft (Crown Point, N.Y.); Sugar Hill Company (Crown Point, N.Y.)
Subjects:
General stores--New York (State)--Crown Point; Grocery trade--New York (State)--Crown Point; Inland water transportation--New York (State)--Accounting.; Iron industry and trade--New York (State)--Crown Point--Accounting.; Business records--New York (State)--Crown Point.; Railroads--New York (State)--Crown Point.
Form and Genre Terms:
Account books.; Ledgers (account books); Payroll records.; Daybooks.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Hammond Family Business Records
Series II. Ledgers
CONTAINER LIST
- Hammond Family Business Records, 19854-1903
  Includes Hammond Store and Crown Point Iron Company
  Listed according to physical arrangement.
  - Hammond & Bros. business correspondence, 1856-04-1856-06 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    re:orders, iron, payments, prices etc.
  - Correspondence, 1856-01-1856-03 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1856-10-1856-12 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1856-07-1856-09 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1867-11 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1860-01-1860-12 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Cashiers' Correspondence, 1859 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1867-06 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1867-08 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1867-09 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1867-12 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1859-05-1859-06 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Checks, 1879 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Payable in goods
  - Cashiers' Correspondence, 1858 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Financial Statements, 1861-1864 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Statements, invoices, board bills
  - Bills, 1902-1903 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    from meat and groceries
  - Check stubs, 1865-06-1865-11 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Cancelled checks, 1814-11-1875-01 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1865-01 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Board Bills (Box 2, Folder 8)
    October
  - March 1868, 1868-03 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Unfiled papers, 1872-1874 (Box 2)
  - Receipts, 1855-1859 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - CF Hammond's bank vouchers, 1865 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1858-01-1858-06 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 4)
    Year unknown
  - Merchants and Mechanics Bank Vouchers, 1860-1861 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Financial Statements, 1858-1859-01-01 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    Statements, lumber sales etc.
  - Financial Statements, 1861 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Market Bank Vouchers, 1854-08-1859-07-22 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Market Bank Vouchers and bank book, 1858-01 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1862-05-1862-06 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Unfiled papers (Box 4)
    Similar types of document to rest of box
  - Correspondence, 1862-11-1862-12 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1862-07-1862-08 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1862-09-1862-10 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Unfiled papers (Box 5)
    Similar type of documents in Box 4; bills for frei8ght included
  - CF Hammonds Financial Statements, 1860-1865 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    Statements, invoices and board bills
  - Canceled checks, 1872 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    with revenue stamps
  - Canceled checks, 1872-1873 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Canceled checks, 1872 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Bank Vouchers, 1873 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Unfiled papers, 1871 (Box 6)
    Including iron statements
  - Cashiers Letters, 1866 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - June 1865, 1865-06 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Furnace Papers (Box 7, Folder 3)
    February
  - Board Bills (Box 7, Folder 4)
    September
  - December 1865, 1865-12 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - December 1866, 1866-12 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - August 1873, 1873-08 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - May 1865, 1865-05 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Cashiers Letters, 1865 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Financial Statements, 1860 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - September 1866, 1866-09 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - August 1866, 1866-08 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - November 1866, 1866-11 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - October 1866, 1866-10 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - September 1865, 1865-09 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - July 1865, 1865-07 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Unfiled papers (Box 7)
  - Cashiers Letters, 1861 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Bringman Orders (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Crown Point Iron Co. Financial Statements, 1860-02-01-1864-01 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    Statement of Account
  - Correspondence, 1865-08 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Cancelled checks, 1873 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Board Bills (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Board and Time (Box 8, Folder 7)
    November Board (bills?)
  - Board (Box 8, Folder 8)
    December Board (bills?)
  - CF Hammond Vouchers, 1868-1868 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Unfiled papers (Box 8)
  - Correspondence, 1862-01-1862-02 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Vouchers, 1867 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1865-02 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - March 1865, 1865-03 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - April 1865, 1865-04 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - CF Hammond Correspondence, 1869-10 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - CF Hammond Correspondence, 1869-09 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - CF Hammond Correspondence, 1869-07 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Merchants and Mechanics Bank check stubs, 1862-11-1863-03-28 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    Merchants and Mechanics Bank
  - Canceled checks, 1873 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Unfiled papers (Box 9)
    Same type as rest of box, including Freight and Clay Statements for 1871
  - March 1866, 1866-03 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Market Bank Vouchers, 1858-01-01-1859-03-20 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Merchants and Mechanics Bank Vouchers, 1858-08-25-1860-04-02 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Union Bank Vouchers CF Hammond Account, 1860-04-12 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1889-07-1889-08 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1859-09-1859-12 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1859-01-1859-06 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Vouchers, 1866 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - April 1866, 1866-04 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - February 1866, 1866-02 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - May 1866, 1866-05 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - CF Hammonds Financial Statements, 1863-1866 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    CF Hammond Settled File Accounts
  - Correspondence, 1857-06-1857-08 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1857-11-1857-12 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1857-04-1857-05 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1857-09-1857-10 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1857-01-1857-03 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - CF Hammond settled accounts, 1867-1870 (Box 11)
    Filed alphabetically in leather folder
  - December 1868, 1868-12 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - May 1868, 1868-05 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - February 1868, 1868-02 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - June 1868, 1868-06 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - CF Hammond Cashier Letters, 1868 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - CF Hammond Correspondence, 1869-06 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - CF Hammonds Correspondence, 1869-02 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - September 1868, 1868-09 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - November 1868, 1868-11 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - October 1868, 1868-10 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - CF Hammond Correspondence, 1869-03 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - CF Hammond Correspondence, 1869-05 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - July 1868, 1868-07 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - August 1868, 1868-08 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - CF Hammond Correspondence, 1869-01 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - April 1868, 1868-04 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - January 1868, 1868-01 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1861-05-1861-08 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, 1861-01-1861-02 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, 1861-03-1861-04 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 1861-09-1861-12 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Unfiled papers (Box 12)
  - CF Hammons Financial Statements, 1870 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    Statement, Invoices, Board Bills etc.
  - J and TH Orders, 1871 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Bills (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Harlan Orders, 1873 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Unfiled papers (Box 13)
    Some are dated 1877
  - Invoices of Crockery - Stationary Wall Paper and Co, 1867 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Orders, 1864 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Merchants and Mechanics Bank Certificates of Deposit (Box 14, Folder 3)
    See Bank Book 1857-01-01 and 1859-07-15
  - Orders, 1865 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - RR Papers for pay, 1872 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - RR Papers for pay, 1872 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - RR Papers for pay, 1872 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Board Bills, 1873-04 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Boards, 1874-09 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - CF Hammond Cashiers Letters, 1864 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - CF Hammond Financial Statements, 1865 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    Statements, Invoices and board bills
  - July 1866, 1866-07 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1867-07 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1867-06 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - June 1866, 1866-06 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Unfiled papers (Box 14)
  - Orders, 1864 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Vouchers, 1856 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Cashiers Letters, 1867 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Board Bills, 1873-07 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Unfiled papers, 1880-1903 (Box 15)
    1880, 1892-1893, 1902-1903 represent only some of the dates
  - Furnace Board Bill, 1873-01 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - CF Hammond Boat Receipts, 1866 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - CF Hammond Boat Receipts, 1869 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Lumber Iron Boat receipt & CF Hammond Inspectors Bills, 1865 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - CF Hammond Boat Receipts, 1867 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - CF Hammond Boat Receipts, 1868 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1867-05 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1867-02 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1867-01 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1867-03 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1867-04 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1867-07 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Financial Statements, 1859 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Hammond Co Union Bank Vouchers and H & Co. balances, 1880, 1892-1893, 1902-1903 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Store Price List (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Spring Memo - Store, 1870 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Barker & Wyman Crown Point Memo, 1871 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Price list for store (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Store Memo, 1870 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Barker & Wyman Crown Point Memo, 1871 (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Memo, 1870 (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - RR Book, 1872 (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - Barker & Wyman Book, 1871 (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - JB & Co Memo Book, 1869 (Box 16, Folder 24)
    J.B. & Co
  - B & H Memo, 1873 (Box 16, Folder 25)
    B&H Memoranda
  - Blank in original document (Box 16, Folder 26)
    No description provided
  - 1856 (Box 16, Folder 27)
  - Store Memo, 1871 (Box 16, Folder 28)
    Store
  - Store Related Material, Spring 1871 (Box 16, Folder 29)
  - Store Related Material, 1895-06-15-1895-08-05 (Box 16, Folder 30)
  - Store Related Material, 1897-03-22-1897-05-11 (Box 16, Folder 31)
  - Store Related Material, 1895-08-06-1895-09-21 (Box 16, Folder 32)
  - Store (Box 16, Folder 33)
  - Nov 15 1889 - Feb 7 1900, 1898-11-15-1900-02-07 (Box 16, Folder 34)
  - Store (Box 16, Folder 35)
  - LR Berry Store Crown Point NY (Box 16, Folder 36)
- Ledgers, 1845-1916
  - Store Day Books, 1872-1880
    Daily store transactions with purchases itemized under customers' names.
    - Store Day Book, 1872-01-19-1872-05-27 (Volume A-1)
    - Store Day Book, 1872-11-12-1873-01-17 (Volume A-2)
    - Store Day Book, 1873-01-18-1873-03-15 (Volume A-3)
    - Crown Point Store Day Book, 1873-03-17-1873-05-21 (Volume A-4)
    - Store Day Book, 1873-05-22-1873-07-09 (Volume A-5)
    - Parker & Wyman Store Day Book, 1873-07-10-1873-09-02 (Volume A-6)
    - Barker & Wyman Crown Point NY Store Day Book, 1873-09-03-1873-10-31 (Volume A-7)
    - Store Day Book, 1873-10-31-1874-01-09 (Volume A-8)
    - Store Day Book, 1874-01-10-1874-03-31 (Volume A-9)
    - John Sabombard P. Marcus Store Day Book, 1874-04-01-1874-06-16 (Volume A-10)
    - Store Day Book, 1874-06-15-1874-08-18 (Volume A-11)
    - Store Day Book, 1874-08-19-1874-10-22 (Volume A-12)
    - Store Day Book, 1874-10-23-1875-01-04 (Volume A-13)
    - Store Day Book, 1875-01-05-1875-04-20 (Volume A-14)
    - Store Day Book, 1875-04-20-1875-06-30 (Volume A-15)
    - Store Day Book, 1875-07-01-1875-09-04 (Volume A-16)
    - Store Day Book, 1875-09-06-1875-11-09 (Volume A-17)
    - Store Day Book, 1875-11-10-1876-01-28 (Volume A-18)
    - Store Day Book, 1876-01-29-1876-04-26 (Volume A-19)
    - Store Day Book, 1876-04-27-1876-07-09 (Volume A-20)
    - Store Day Book, 1876-07-08-1876-10-06 (Volume A-21)
    - Store Day Book, 1876-10-07-1877-01-22 (Volume A-22)
    - Store Day Book, 1877-01-23-1877-05-19 (Volume A-23)
    - Store Day Book, 1877-05-19-1877-08-23 (Volume A-24)
    - Store Day Book, 1877-08-24-1877-10-31 (Volume A-25)
    - Store Day Book, 1877-11-01-1878-01-08 (Volume A-26)
    - Store Day Book, 1878-01-08-1878-04-08 (Volume A-27)
    - Store Day Book, 1878-04-09-1878-06-22 (Volume A-28)
    - Store Day Book (Volume A-29)
    - Store Day Book (Volume A-30)
    - Store Day Book (Volume A-31)
    - Store Day Book (Volume A-32)
    - Store Day Book (Volume A-33)
    - Store Day Book (Volume A-34)
    - Store Day Book (Volume A-35)
    - Store Day Book (Volume A-36)
    - Store Day Book (Volume A-37)
    - Store Day Book (Volume A-38)
  - Furnace Store Day Books, 1874-1880
    - Furnace Store Day Book (Volume B-1)
    - Furnace Store Day Book (Volume B-2)
    - Furnace Store Day Book (Volume B-3)
    - Furnace Store Day Book (Volume B-4)
    - Furnace Store Day Book (Volume B-5)
    - Furnace Store Day Book (Volume B-6)
    - Furnace Store Day Book (Volume B-7)
    - Furnace Store Day Book (Volume B-8)
  - Odd Store Day Books, 1845-1905
    - Odd Store Day Book (Volume C-1)
      Itemized by customer debit/credit amount
    - Odd Store Day Book (Volume C-2)
    - Odd Store Day Book (Volume C-3)
    - EJ Baker and Co Delivery Book Odd Store Day Book (Volume C-4)
      Daily record of purchases to be delivered
    - Reynolds Consecutive Book Odd Store Day Book (Volume C-5)
    - Odd Store Day Book (Volume C-6)
    - WE Petty Odd Store Day Book (Volume C-7)
    - Barker and Co Odd Store Day Book (Volume C-8)
    - LR Berry Crown Point NY Odd Store Day Book (Volume C-9)
      Broadway and Maiden Lane Brick Store on the Corner
    - RR Book Odd Store Day Book (Volume C-10)
  - Customer Ledgers, 1864-1900
    Entries transferred from store day book.
    - J & T Hammond Customer Ledger (Volume D-1)
    - Customer Ledgers (Volume D-2)
    - Customer Ledgers (Volume D-3)
    - Customer Ledgers (Volume D-4)
    - Customer Ledgers, 1886-1880-08-21 (Volume D-5)
    - Customer Ledgers (Volume D-6)
    - Customer Ledgers - O (Volume D-7)
    - Customer Ledgers - D (Volume D-8)
    - Customer Ledgers - F (Volume D-9)
    - Customer Ledgers - G (Volume D-10)
    - Customer Ledgers (Volume D-11)
  - Master Customer Ledgers, 1871-1875
    - Master Customer Ledgers No. 24 (Volume E-1)
    - Master Customer Ledgers (Volume E-2)
    - Master Customer Ledgers No. 2 (Volume E-3)
    - Master Customer Ledgers No. 3 - Furnace Store (Volume F-1)
    - Master Customer Ledgers - Furnace Store (Volume F-2)
  - Check Books, 1878-1916
    - Checks National Bank Troy - Check Books / Stubs (Volume G-1)
    - Check Books / Stubs (Volume G-2)
    - Wyman, Banker Check Books / Stubs (Volume G-3)
    - Check Books / Stubs (Volume G-4)
      Two filled out checks on JW Wyman. Banker
  - Store Inventory Lists, 1874-1892
    - Store Inventory Lists (Volume H-1)
    - Store Inventory Lists (Volume H-2)
    - Store Inventory Lists (Volume H-3)
    - Reynolds Consecutive Want Book (Volume H-4)
  - Order Books, 1876-1905
    - Order Book - 1887-1881 Order Book (Volume I-1)
    - WB Viall Crown Point Essex Co. Market Barker and Wyman Dealers - Order Book (Volume I-2)
      in dry goods, groceries, hats, caps, boots, shoes, iron, steel, nails etc.
    - G Taft Turk - Order Book (Volume I-3)
    - Order Book (Volume I-4)
  - Dash Books, 1851-1880
    - Cash Book 1851-1854 (Volume J-1)
    - J & T Hammond Store - Cash Book (Volume J-2)
    - Cash Book (Volume J-3)
    - Cash Book (Volume J-4)
    - Cash Book (Volume J-5)
    - Cash Book - Furnace Store (Volume J-6)
  - Miscellaneous Store Accounts, 1878-1898
    - Miscellaneous Store Accounts (Volume K-1)
      Seems to be record of customer payment to company
    - Miscellaneous Store Accounts (Volume K-2)
      Seems to be record of cost of stock. Dry goods & notions, crockery and stoneware, groceries etc.
  - Account Books
    Possibly used by both the Hammond Store and the Crown Point Iron Company or impossible to determine or miscellaneous.
    - Bill Book Antoine Delona District 3 Rivers River Du Loup C E (Volume L-1)
    - Bill Book (Volume L-2)
    - Cash Book (Volume L-3)
      Possibly used by CF Hammond
    - Cash Book (Volume L-4)
    - Hammond & Co Accounts Book (Volume L-5)
      Seems to be cash book
    - CF Hammond Day Book (Volume L-6)
    - Account Books (Volume L-7)
      Seems to be concerned with banks and checks. Fragments of other books inserted
    - Account Books - Ledger (Volume L-8)
    - Highway Accounts - Account Book (Volume L-9)
      Probably used by CF Hammond as a highway commissioner
    - Sugar Hill Co. Time Book (Volume L-10)
      Hours, daily rates and monthly wages
    - Boat G T Morehouse Book (Volume L-11)
      Better be preserved as a memorandum TH, pages all torn out
  - Bank Books, 1835-1866
    - Bank of Whitehall with Hammond and Co No. 1 - Bank Book (Volume M-1)
    - Merchants and Mechanics Bank of Troy with CF Hammond and Co. Bank Book (Volume M-2)
    - Market Bank with Hammond and Co. Bank Book (Volume M-3)
    - Bank of Whitehall with Hammond and Co Bank Book (Volume M-4)
    - Merchants and Mechanics Bank of Troy with CF Hammond and Co. Bank Book (Volume M-5)
    - Union Bank of Troy with CF Hammond (Volume M-6)
    - Merchants and Mechanics Bank of Troy with CF Hammond and Co. No 1 Bank Book (Volume M-7)
    - Merchants and Mechanics Bank of Troy with CF Hammond and Co No 2 Bank Book (Volume M-8)
    - National Union Bank of Troy with CF Hammond (Volume M-9)
    - Merchants and Mechanics Bank of Troy with CF Hammond and Co No 3 - Bank Book (Volume M-10)
  - Check Book Stubs, 1855-1883
    Often on different banks for parallel periods. Probably used for both store and iron company.
    - Hammond and Co Blank Drafts Check Book Stubs (Volume N-1)
    - Merchants and Mechanics Bank Checks Check Book Stubs (Volume N-2)
    - Union Bank of Troy with CF Hammond and Co Check Book Stubs (Volume N-3)
    - Union Bank Checks Check Book Stubs (Volume N-4)
    - Merchants and Mechanics Bank Checks Check Book Stubs (Volume N-5)
    - Union Bank Checks Check Book Stubs (Volume N-6)
    - Check Stubs J & T. H and Co Check Book Stubs (Volume N-7)
    - Check Stubs J & T. H and Co and CPI Co. (Volume N-10)
    - CF Hammond Check Book Stubs (Volume N-11)
    - CF Hammond Check Book Stubs (Volume N-12)
    - Check Book Stubs (Volume N-13)